<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="wlr_color_unstable_v1">

  <interface name="zwlr_ctm_manager_v1" version="1">

    <request name="get_ctm_control">
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zwlr_ctm_control_v1"/>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwlr_ctm_control_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="adjust ctm for an output">
      This interface allows a client to adjust gamma tables for a particular
      output.

      The client will receive the gamma size, and will then be able to set gamma
      tables. At any time the compositor can send a failed event indicating that
      this object is no longer valid.

      There must always be at most one gamma control object per output, which
      has exclusive access to this particular output. When the gamma control
      object is destroyed, the color table is restored to its original value.
    </description>

    <!-- <event name="gamma_size"> -->
    <!--   <description summary="size of gamma ramps"> -->
    <!--     Advertise the size of each gamma ramp. -->

    <!--     This event is sent immediately when the gamma control object is created. -->
    <!--   </description> -->
    <!--   <arg name="size" type="uint" summary="number of elements in a ramp"/> -->
    <!-- </event> -->

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="invalid_ctm" value="1" summary="invalid ctm"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="set_ctm">
      <description summary="set the gamma table">
        Set the gamma table. The file descriptor can be memory-mapped to provide
        the raw gamma table, which contains successive gamma ramps for the red,
        green and blue channels. Each gamma ramp is an array of 16-byte unsigned
        integers which has the same length as the gamma size.

        The file descriptor data must have the same length as three times the
        gamma size.
      </description>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd" summary="gamma table file descriptor"/>
    </request>

    <event name="failed">
      <description summary="object no longer valid">
        This event indicates that the color control is no longer valid. This
        can happen for a number of reasons, including:
        - The output doesn't support color tables
        - Setting the color tables failed
        - Another client already has exclusive color control for this output
        - The compositor has transferred color control to another client

        Upon receiving this event, the client should destroy this object.
      </description>
    </event>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy this control">
        Destroys the color control object. If the object is still valid, this
        restores the original color table.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
